<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://familien-transformation.de/en/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://familien-transformation.de/en/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2023-01-14T10:33:18+00:00</updated><id>https://familien-transformation.de/en/feed.xml</id><title type="html">global.title</title><subtitle>global.description</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The fundamental right to GRIEF</title><link href="https://familien-transformation.de/en/philosophie/2020/07/17/trauer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The fundamental right to GRIEF" /><published>2020-07-17T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-07-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://familien-transformation.de/en/philosophie/2020/07/17/trauer</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://familien-transformation.de/en/philosophie/2020/07/17/trauer/">&lt;p&gt;Sure, if someone dies you can - or you even have to grieve. This is where most people understand most easily that griefing is the emotion that enables the loved one to let go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if a child has to let go of something, especially if it is something unimportant or a trifle from the evaluation of an adult, then the child should not grieve but function properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the knowledge that griefing is the emotion that allows you to let go, it is the most sensible solution to grief if I want to or have to let go of something instead of trying to persuade you that it is not bad at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even as a well-behaved adult, I sometimes have moments when I find it difficult to let go of seemingly minor things. If I allow the feeling of grief in such a case, I have often experienced that letting go and accepting what is much easier is easier for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I noticed that there can be other feelings before the grief, i.e. before letting go and acceptance. If that is the case, then letting go is only possible when I come to terms with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have had the experience with my children that if I manage to let them be in your grief (however it expresses itself - loud sobs, soft tears, …) and, if necessary, to accompany them with understanding and consolation, such situations run more beneficial for all of us&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Miriam</name></author><category term="philosophie" /><summary type="html">Sure, if someone dies you can - or you even have to grieve. This is where most people understand most easily that griefing is the emotion that enables the loved one to let go.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The confessional trauma</title><link href="https://familien-transformation.de/en/impression/2020/06/06/beichtstuhl/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The confessional trauma" /><published>2020-06-06T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-06-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://familien-transformation.de/en/impression/2020/06/06/beichtstuhl</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://familien-transformation.de/en/impression/2020/06/06/beichtstuhl/">&lt;p&gt;Did you have to go to the Catholic Church to confess as a child? I remember creepy feelings: cold and dark church, moldy confessional in the far corner of the church, incomprehensible rules, unknown pastor and always X Lord’s Prayer for forgiving sins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In class in elementary school and from my grandmother, I then learned that sinners do not go to heaven but to hell. Since of course I had to repent after every confession, my subconscious has made me a sinner and the trauma is done) -:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By precisely feeling my feelings and questioning all strange behavior, I realize today that a lot more has come of it. For example, there is the 4th commandment “You should honor your father and your mother”. Since my subconscious does not want to go to hell, it forbids me any criticism of my parents today and thus keeps me dependent on my parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S .: Thanks to my wife, I converted from the Catholic to the Evangelical Church 10 years ago and I am now getting rid of the confessional and penance.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Markus</name></author><category term="impression" /><summary type="html">Did you have to go to the Catholic Church to confess as a child? I remember creepy feelings: cold and dark church, moldy confessional in the far corner of the church, incomprehensible rules, unknown pastor and always X Lord’s Prayer for forgiving sins.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The uncertainty of the mother’s son</title><link href="https://familien-transformation.de/en/impression/2020/05/28/uncertainty/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The uncertainty of the mother's son" /><published>2020-05-28T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-05-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://familien-transformation.de/en/impression/2020/05/28/uncertainty</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://familien-transformation.de/en/impression/2020/05/28/uncertainty/">&lt;p&gt;As a man, I still long for my mother’s love at the age of 39. In marriage I look for a mother substitute in my wife. In literature one speaks of a “mother son”. Grrr, doesn’t sound that great and I want to get rid of it as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a high level of need for recognition and love among the mother’s son husbands. This is shown (also for me) by a high degree of uncertainty. The man can only do a little himself and needs confirmation from his wife for everything: “Is that enough vinegar on the salad?”, “Is that the right cleaning agent?”, “5 rolls are enough for breakfast”, “I don’t understand, can you explain that to me? “,” does the shirt match the pants? “ and many more questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not my wife’s job to satisfy this need. I first have to become aware of this need myself and then fill it myself. &lt;a href=&quot;/inspiration&quot;&gt;Mindful Self Compassion&lt;/a&gt; (MSC) gave me the first impulses to love myself and to become independent of my mother. Today I watch myself how often I ask my wife something and use this as a barometer for my insecurity.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Markus</name></author><category term="impression" /><summary type="html">As a man, I still long for my mother’s love at the age of 39. In marriage I look for a mother substitute in my wife. In literature one speaks of a “mother son”. Grrr, doesn’t sound that great and I want to get rid of it as soon as possible.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Long-term living together requires careful observation of needs</title><link href="https://familien-transformation.de/en/impression/2020/04/09/windelei/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Long-term living together requires careful observation of needs" /><published>2020-04-09T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-04-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://familien-transformation.de/en/impression/2020/04/09/windelei</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://familien-transformation.de/en/impression/2020/04/09/windelei/">&lt;p&gt;Put a baby into the world, now that the world is upside down. What does that do to you? How can it be endured? An inspiring interview in German by Sonja from &lt;a href=&quot;https://windelei.de&quot;&gt;Windelei Berlin&lt;/a&gt; with Markus about Corona Virus, free learning and traveling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… the constant coexistence of parents and children is “normal” for us. Our goal is to meet our children at eye level, to live in community and to support them wherever necessary. Everyone can express their needs with us and we look together - usually at the breakfast table - for the necessary steps to fulfill them. Our experience shows that rules or tips only work for a short time. Long-term living together requires careful observation of children’s needs and the creation of a permanent, stress-free and relaxed attitude (of the parents). We have summarized a few of our approaches in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/2020/03/16/homeoffice/&quot;&gt;Blog&lt;/a&gt;. …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read the entire interview in German here:
&lt;a href=&quot;https://windelei.de/2020/04/09/ein-frischgewordener-papa-erzaehlt-durch-corona-gibt-es-keine-aeusserlichen-anreize-dass-wir-zu-frueh-das-haus-verlassen&quot;&gt;https://windelei.de/2020/04/09/ein-frischgewordener-papa-erzaehlt-durch-corona-gibt-es-keine-aeusserlichen-anreize-dass-wir-zu-frueh-das-haus-verlassen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Markus</name></author><category term="impression" /><summary type="html">Put a baby into the world, now that the world is upside down. What does that do to you? How can it be endured? An inspiring interview in German by Sonja from Windelei Berlin with Markus about Corona Virus, free learning and traveling.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Transformation processes don’t feel easy - or what is transformation?</title><link href="https://familien-transformation.de/en/philosophie/2020/02/03/transformation-leicht/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Transformation processes don't feel easy - or what is transformation?" /><published>2020-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://familien-transformation.de/en/philosophie/2020/02/03/transformation-leicht</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://familien-transformation.de/en/philosophie/2020/02/03/transformation-leicht/">&lt;p&gt;Transformation happens through change in me. To start the change process, I question my beliefs. I allow something new and thus unknown to me to come in and in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-do-i-start-this-change-process&quot;&gt;How do I start this change process?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By taking sole responsibility for me in all situations that seem to go wrong between myself and others or between me and the world.
This step usually triggers resistance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why&quot;&gt;Why?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have all learned that the “other” who behaved incorrectly according to social laws is responsible for making me feel good again. To do this, he should recognize his mistake, acknowledge and apologize to me and “make amends” as far as possible. If that doesn’t happen, we’ll get into trouble. How do we get there now that we can feel good again? If we have been wronged, it seems that it is impossible for us to feel good until this injustice is recognized and the perpetrator is held responsible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This view means that we are caught in a dependency on another. We are only released from the situation if he does something specific. Change in me, that is transformation, means that I withdraw from this dependency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how&quot;&gt;How?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By taking responsibility for my own feelings and daring to feel the pain caused by the situation in me. It sounds easy at first, but it is not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-1&quot;&gt;Why?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nobody likes to feel pain or a feeling other than negative. As a rule, we have trained throughout our lives to do everything to avoid having to feel negative feelings or to get rid of them as quickly as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many ways to feel the negative feelings so that they no longer keep us trapped. You can only find the best one for yourself by trying it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were helped by Mike Helwig with radical permission, Safi Nidiaye and Ms. Gebauer with body-centered heart work, Simone Frese with kinesiology, Brad Blanton and Tulia Syvänen with radical honesty. Here you can find more about our &lt;a href=&quot;/inspiration&quot;&gt;Inspirations&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Miriam</name></author><category term="philosophie" /><summary type="html">Transformation happens through change in me. To start the change process, I question my beliefs. I allow something new and thus unknown to me to come in and in.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What is the difference between change management and “inside-out transformation”?</title><link href="https://familien-transformation.de/en/philosophie/2020/01/30/insideout/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is the difference between change management and &quot;inside-out transformation&quot;?" /><published>2020-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://familien-transformation.de/en/philosophie/2020/01/30/insideout</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://familien-transformation.de/en/philosophie/2020/01/30/insideout/">&lt;p&gt;There is an outside change in a change process. This means that any processes or procedures in your life have to be changed. If e.g. If you move to work 30 minutes longer, you have to set your alarm clock 30 minutes ahead to get to work on time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our inside-out transformations, we look at what we have in ourselves and what we need in ourselves to be happy and satisfied. It’s about finding the needs or feelings in us. For example, you may find yourself waking up without an alarm. In our transformation processes we look at the way to find and fulfill this need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A big challenge is that we mostly have resistance to these inner needs. Trained by many years of adhering to processes (alarm clock 6:30 a.m.) or external social requirements, this need seems wrong to us. This has to be felt and accepted. Often the first inner need is only the outer of our “inner onion”. It may well be that there is a much larger one under the first need. Under the need to wake up without an alarm clock, e.g. there is a need for a self-determined morning. In the course of a transformation, you may set your alarm clock again 30 minutes earlier and treat yourself to a refreshing forest run to start the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inner needs become challenging when we are a family or group of people or team at work. Then it helps to talk about our needs and to find a way to a happy and balanced life together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, my inner needs trigger great resistance first. I usually find 2 or 3 other layers under my needs and in the end I feel much happier, more secure and above all more authentic with my new processes or approaches.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Markus</name></author><category term="philosophie" /><summary type="html">There is an outside change in a change process. This means that any processes or procedures in your life have to be changed. If e.g. If you move to work 30 minutes longer, you have to set your alarm clock 30 minutes ahead to get to work on time.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bullying</title><link href="https://familien-transformation.de/en/philosophie/2019/12/03/bullying/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bullying" /><published>2019-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://familien-transformation.de/en/philosophie/2019/12/03/bullying</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://familien-transformation.de/en/philosophie/2019/12/03/bullying/">&lt;p&gt;Bullying victims have doubts about their own worth and give the power to answer the question of their worth to the outside world. At the same time, there is a hunch that their worthlessness is wrong. This leads to a desperate conflict in the bullying victim, which in the worst case can lead to suicide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The (bullying) perpetrator also has doubts about its value, but also gets the answer from outside (and therefore just as worthless). In contrast to the victim, however, this happens proactively through the humiliation of others. He intuitively recognizes the possible victims, since the two of them (victim and perpetrator) are connected by doubts about their value. In contrast to the victim, the perpetrator is not afraid to inflict suffering on others in order to remove his doubts. One is an active shadow and the other a passive one according to the &lt;a href=&quot;/inspiration&quot;&gt;“shadow principle” by Rüdiger Dahlke&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bullying victims and perpetrators must take full responsibility for their worthlessness in order to get out of the bullying process. The realization that an external judgment determines your own original value is one of the first steps. Mike Helwig helped us along the way with radical permission and Safi Nidiaye and Ms. Gebauer with body-centered heart work. Here you can find more about our &lt;a href=&quot;/inspiration&quot;&gt;Inspirations&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Partners of bullying victims and perpetrators are also facing a major challenge. You are constantly asked to give the bully victim / perpetrator from outside. As a result, they cause more doubts about worthlessness and / or suffer from the pressure of the bully. Often, the partners can only escape the doubts about the values ​​of the victims of the bullying.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Miriam</name></author><category term="philosophie" /><summary type="html">Bullying victims have doubts about their own worth and give the power to answer the question of their worth to the outside world. At the same time, there is a hunch that their worthlessness is wrong. This leads to a desperate conflict in the bullying victim, which in the worst case can lead to suicide.</summary></entry></feed>