<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://familien-transformation.de/en/feed/impression.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://familien-transformation.de/en/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2023-01-14T10:19:28+00:00</updated><id>https://familien-transformation.de/en/feed/impression.xml</id><title type="html">global.title | Impression</title><subtitle>global.description</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The confessional trauma</title><link href="https://familien-transformation.de/en/impression/2020/06/06/beichtstuhl/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The confessional trauma" /><published>2020-06-06T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-06-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://familien-transformation.de/en/impression/2020/06/06/beichtstuhl</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://familien-transformation.de/en/impression/2020/06/06/beichtstuhl/">&lt;p&gt;Did you have to go to the Catholic Church to confess as a child? I remember creepy feelings: cold and dark church, moldy confessional in the far corner of the church, incomprehensible rules, unknown pastor and always X Lord’s Prayer for forgiving sins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In class in elementary school and from my grandmother, I then learned that sinners do not go to heaven but to hell. Since of course I had to repent after every confession, my subconscious has made me a sinner and the trauma is done) -:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By precisely feeling my feelings and questioning all strange behavior, I realize today that a lot more has come of it. For example, there is the 4th commandment “You should honor your father and your mother”. Since my subconscious does not want to go to hell, it forbids me any criticism of my parents today and thus keeps me dependent on my parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S .: Thanks to my wife, I converted from the Catholic to the Evangelical Church 10 years ago and I am now getting rid of the confessional and penance.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Markus</name></author><category term="impression" /><summary type="html">Did you have to go to the Catholic Church to confess as a child? I remember creepy feelings: cold and dark church, moldy confessional in the far corner of the church, incomprehensible rules, unknown pastor and always X Lord’s Prayer for forgiving sins.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The uncertainty of the mother’s son</title><link href="https://familien-transformation.de/en/impression/2020/05/28/uncertainty/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The uncertainty of the mother's son" /><published>2020-05-28T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-05-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://familien-transformation.de/en/impression/2020/05/28/uncertainty</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://familien-transformation.de/en/impression/2020/05/28/uncertainty/">&lt;p&gt;As a man, I still long for my mother’s love at the age of 39. In marriage I look for a mother substitute in my wife. In literature one speaks of a “mother son”. Grrr, doesn’t sound that great and I want to get rid of it as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a high level of need for recognition and love among the mother’s son husbands. This is shown (also for me) by a high degree of uncertainty. The man can only do a little himself and needs confirmation from his wife for everything: “Is that enough vinegar on the salad?”, “Is that the right cleaning agent?”, “5 rolls are enough for breakfast”, “I don’t understand, can you explain that to me? “,” does the shirt match the pants? “ and many more questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not my wife’s job to satisfy this need. I first have to become aware of this need myself and then fill it myself. &lt;a href=&quot;/inspiration&quot;&gt;Mindful Self Compassion&lt;/a&gt; (MSC) gave me the first impulses to love myself and to become independent of my mother. Today I watch myself how often I ask my wife something and use this as a barometer for my insecurity.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Markus</name></author><category term="impression" /><summary type="html">As a man, I still long for my mother’s love at the age of 39. In marriage I look for a mother substitute in my wife. In literature one speaks of a “mother son”. Grrr, doesn’t sound that great and I want to get rid of it as soon as possible.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Long-term living together requires careful observation of needs</title><link href="https://familien-transformation.de/en/impression/2020/04/09/windelei/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Long-term living together requires careful observation of needs" /><published>2020-04-09T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-04-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://familien-transformation.de/en/impression/2020/04/09/windelei</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://familien-transformation.de/en/impression/2020/04/09/windelei/">&lt;p&gt;Put a baby into the world, now that the world is upside down. What does that do to you? How can it be endured? An inspiring interview in German by Sonja from &lt;a href=&quot;https://windelei.de&quot;&gt;Windelei Berlin&lt;/a&gt; with Markus about Corona Virus, free learning and traveling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… the constant coexistence of parents and children is “normal” for us. Our goal is to meet our children at eye level, to live in community and to support them wherever necessary. Everyone can express their needs with us and we look together - usually at the breakfast table - for the necessary steps to fulfill them. Our experience shows that rules or tips only work for a short time. Long-term living together requires careful observation of children’s needs and the creation of a permanent, stress-free and relaxed attitude (of the parents). We have summarized a few of our approaches in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/2020/03/16/homeoffice/&quot;&gt;Blog&lt;/a&gt;. …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read the entire interview in German here:
&lt;a href=&quot;https://windelei.de/2020/04/09/ein-frischgewordener-papa-erzaehlt-durch-corona-gibt-es-keine-aeusserlichen-anreize-dass-wir-zu-frueh-das-haus-verlassen&quot;&gt;https://windelei.de/2020/04/09/ein-frischgewordener-papa-erzaehlt-durch-corona-gibt-es-keine-aeusserlichen-anreize-dass-wir-zu-frueh-das-haus-verlassen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Markus</name></author><category term="impression" /><summary type="html">Put a baby into the world, now that the world is upside down. What does that do to you? How can it be endured? An inspiring interview in German by Sonja from Windelei Berlin with Markus about Corona Virus, free learning and traveling.</summary></entry></feed>